

🖂 atyoung1997@gmail.com 📞 (262)-366-8412 🕈 Chicago, IL in www.linkedin.com/in/adam--young 🗘 atyoung1997



# **SUMMARY**

Aspiring data science professional with two years of experience performing data analysis and delivering results to stakeholders in a management consulting environment. Currently enrolled in Springboard's intensive six-month Data Science Certification Program where I have had hands-on experience using Python and SQL to perform data wrangling, data visualization, exploratory data analysis, model selection, and model evaluation. Seeking a full-time position where I can apply my project management, communication and technical skills to help businesses solve problems with data.

## **SKILLS**

LANGUAGES: Python (Pandas, NumPy, Scikit-learn, SciPy, statsmodels, TensorFlow), SQL, R, VBA, Git

DATA VISUALIZATION: Matplotlib, Seaborn, ggplot2, Microsoft Excel, Microsoft Powerpoint

MACHINE LEARNING: Linear Regression, Logistic Regression, Regularization, SVM's, kNN, Ensemble Methods (Boosting and Bagging), K-Means Clustering, Hierarchical Clustering, PCA, Cross Validation, Bias-Variance Tradeoff, Hypothesis Testing, A/B Testing, Neural Networks

**DISTRIBUTED COMPUTING:** Hadoop, MapReduce, Apache Spark, PySpark

## PROJECTS AND EXAMS

### **Predictive Analytics Exam – Society of Actuaries**

Jun 2020

- Five-hour exam which involved using R to perform data cleaning, feature selection, model selection, and model validation, along with writing a report that summarized and communicated the findings to a non-technical audience.
- R packages used: ggplot2, dplyr, Caret, XGBoost, glmnet

#### Video Game Sales Data Analysis and Classification

May 2021

- Evaluated multiple classification models on a Kaggle video game sales dataset. Performed data cleaning, exploratory data analysis, model selection, and model validation. Ultimately used a cross-validated grid search to tune the final random forest classifier's hyperparameters.
- Python libraries used: Pandas, NumPy, Scikit-learn, Matplotlib, Seaborn, pickle

# **EMPLOYMENT**

#### Mercer Health & Benefits, Senior Actuarial Analyst, Chicago, IL

Jun 2019 - Jan 2021

Provided analysis supporting all aspects of clients' medical, dental and vision benefit plans. This includes underwriting, budget reporting, reserving, strategy, and compliance. Responsibilities extended from gathering the data all the way through to delivering results directly to client leadership.

- Saved an estimated 10 hours of time each quarter by creating a custom dashboard reporting process for a complex manufacturing client.
- Marketed and placed over 20 stop loss insurance policies as part of Mercer's Stop Loss Center of Excellence. Gathered large-claimant data, solicited quotes from carriers, negotiated with carriers, and created final client deliverables.
- Worked on development of Mercer's proprietary network analysis tool which analyzed the cost differential of medical carriers based on the geographic distribution of a client's population. This tool was routinely used to inform a client's decision when marketing their medical coverage.

Mercer Health & Benefits, Actuarial Analyst Intern, Chicago, IL

May 2018 - Aug 2018

Flad Development & Investment Corp., Accounting Intern, Madison, WI

May 2017 – Aug 2017

### **EDUCATION**

#### Springboard Data Science Career Track

Feb 2021 - Present

Six-month intensive course in data science, machine learning, Python, SQL.

University of Wisconsin - Madison - B.B.A

Sep 2015 - May 2019

Majors in Actuarial Science and Risk Management and Insurance – 3.84 GPA

Jun 2016 – Jun 2020

Actuarial Exams Passed - P, FM, C, LTAM, IFM, PA